Nick Coleman

Full Stack Developer

Google Voice: 435.200.3347

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a full stack web developer, living in Park City, Utah. I first started coding as an IBM Assembly Language Programmer on Missile-Space Track systems in the US Air Force. And, I spent my Air Force career in the IT field managing computercommunications infrastructure and software projects. Post military I worked with a number of start-up software companies. I eventually started my own business that focuses on customer relationship management software.

I've always loved the creative process and teamwork that goes into developing a software product. I refocused my second career into that passion as a software developer. That included completing a four-month bootcamp at Thinkful with a ReactJS and React-Native focus.

SPECIALTIES

Clean, Efficient Code

New Innovative Technologies



Problem Solving

Critical **Thinking**



Pair Programming



Team Work

LANGUAGES, LIBRARIES, and FRAMEWORKS







React

React-Native

JavaScript ES6







MongoDB

Node.js

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATION

BS – Computer Science Masters - Computer Resources Management Project Management Professional (PMP #1342546)

nick@nickcoleman.io

http://www.NickColeman.io LinkedIn: nick-coleman

EXPERIENCE

Owner - Nick Coleman, LLC

2005-Present

I run a small business that develops customer relationship management (CRM) software enabling realtors to increase their productivity and sales volumes by effectively managing their client base and transactions. I also augmented this with iOS apps that help consumers understand the cost of home ownership.

As continuing education, I completed a four-month fulltime, full stack bootcamp with Thinkful.com that focused on ReactJS and React-Native. And, I also volunteered as a bootcamp mentor for Pando Labs (a non-profit organization) to teach Front-End web development (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js) to low-income, service-level employees.

Software Project Manager – Ameritege

2000-2003

I was a founding employee of a technology company that acquired mature enterprise software businesses and provided software-consulting services. I managed Software Projects, Operations, and Consulting Services. This also included managing offshore development staff in both enterprise and startup environments.

IT Director - Aonix

1997-2000

Aonix was created from three international companies that developed software modeling tools and software compilers. I ran their US and European IT operations and was responsible for successfully merging disparate IT infrastructure, communications systems, contracts and technical staff.

US Air Force

1978-1997

I retired as a Lieutenant Colonel and spent my career as an Information Technology officer with positions ranging from:

- IT Director for the Defense Special Weapons Agency -managed/tracked US nuclear weapons stockpile
- IT Director for the Secretary of the Air Force -- ran the IT infrastructure including software development
- Network Operations Director for Defense Information Systems Agency -- managed and architected the military's internet backbone in Europe
- IBM Assembly Language programmer -- developed software that tracked deep space objects and ballistic missiles

HOBBIES

Running, Skiing, Fly Fishing, Off-Roading,